forrester.com 2019-12-17

# Privacy Policy · Forrester

## Privacy Policy

Forrester respects your privacy. The type of information and ways we collect and use the information you provide while on our website (“Website”), Forrester mobile applications (“Apps”) or our Tap Application (“Tap”, and collectively with our Website and Apps, the “Site”) and during certain other interactions are listed below:

###  When does Forrester collect information? 

Forrester may collect certain information when an individual:

  * Registers for use of the Site or uses the Site.
  * Registers for use of the Forrester online communities or posts information on a shared area of the Site.
  * Purchases certain products or services from us.
  * Registers for one of our events or webinars.
  * Seeks employment opportunities with Forrester.
  * Wishes to obtain more information about our products and services. 

To the press: Forrester obtains contact details and other personal information regarding media contacts and influencers from a variety of sources. If you wish to know more about how such information is collected and used, please contact [press@forrester.com](mailto:press@forrester.com) for more information.

###  What information does Forrester collect? 

  * Personal contact information you may choose to provide while visiting or registering on our Site, including registrations to attend Forrester events. This information may include your: name, address, company name, job title, telephone number, email address, and the name and email of third parties you may provide to us. 
  * If you register to participate in Forrester online communities or other shared areas of the Site, you may be asked to create a profile. Your profile may be made available to other members of the shared site(s) and may include the registration information you provide as well as other information you choose to add such as work history and education.
  * Behavioral information about how you use the Site and your IP address.
  * If you are using Tap, we collect the content you post, link, store, share or otherwise make available on Tap, including text, links, photos, graphics, audio, videos, location data or other material (“Your Taps”). If you connect to your Facebook account, then we will also receive your name, email address, friend list and public profile information from Facebook. We receive your location data when you use Tap so that we can provide relevant suggestions of nearby companies and brands for Your Taps.
  * If you are applying for a job at Forrester, we may also collect your resume, work history, and education if you choose to provide or upload your resume via the Site.

###  How does Forrester use the information? 

**To fulfill our obligations.** Forrester uses personal contact information you share with us to fulfill contractual obligations that may include providing products or services that you or your employer purchased, answer your contract administration related inquiries or communicate with you about your account or transactions with us, and send you information about features on the Site, or changes to our policies or events for which you registered.

**To provide Tap.** If you are using Tap, Your Taps are publicly available on the application. We may use Your Taps in a number of different ways, including displaying them, reformatting them, incorporating them into other works, creating derivative works from them, promoting them and distributing them.

  * We may also share Your Taps with third party businesses so that they can improve their products and services and provide responses to Your Taps.
  * If you use Tap, we may also send you communications about Your Taps, your account and the Tap application to facilitate your use of the application.
  * If you choose to connect to your Facebook account on Tap, your name or user ID that you use with Facebook will be publicly displayed along with Your Taps and such information may be viewed by and shared with third party businesses.

**To improve research, the Site and measure effectiveness.** Forrester regularly analyzes data pertaining to visitor trends, research consumption, and research grading to improve our research, plan site enhancements, and measure overall site effectiveness.

**To answer job search inquiries. We use your submitted information to respond to inquiries you make regarding job postings.**

**To maintain a secure Site.** IP addresses are collected in order to maintain our Site security and ensure access to restricted portions of the Site is limited to authorized users.

**To improve our performance by using third party vendors.** We may also disclose certain data to third party contractors or vendors in connection with their performance of services to us. Contractual agreements between us and such third parties provide that your information will be kept confidential and secure.

**To conduct Forrester Events.** When registering for an event you may choose to have your name, title, company and/or country be available to event attendees during the event. Forrester transfers certain information of event registrants and attendees to its event sponsors. Use by Sponsors of the information you choose to share with them is subject to each sponsor’s Privacy Policy. Please click the link found in the Registration Terms and Conditions of the specific Event for further information. For details on how Forrester shares your information with sponsors please see below:

  * **Pre-Event Lists.** Sponsors of a Forrester event are provided a “Pre-Event List” for event staffing purposes. The list may contain the Company name, title, industry and country of individuals that have registered for the event.
  * **Post-Event Lists** – When registering for an event you may choose to have your contact details (name, title, company, and/or country) added to a “Post-Event List” that is transferred to sponsors of the event for marketing purposes.
  * **Event Sponsor Booth Lists.** Forum event attendees are provided with badges having bar codes that may be scanned at sponsored activities or sponsor booths. Attendee contact information is transferred to any sponsor that scans the badge.
  * **Sponsored Event Lists and RFID badge scanning.** When attending an event session sponsored by a third party, your badge may be scanned. Attendee contact information is transferred to any sponsor that scans the badge. Radio frequency identification **(RFID)** technology may be used to scan a badge when attending certain sponsored sessions at events held in the United States. Please note that signage outside such sponsored sessions will alert an attendee if the **RFID** functionality of a badge is being used at that session. If so, by walking into these sessions you agree to have your badge automatically scanned and your contact information shared with the session sponsor.

**To send you marketing emails subject to your opt-in.** If you opt into such communications, Forrester may use your email address to send periodic promotional emails and special offers.

**To enable Forrester online communities.** If you participate in Forrester online communities or other shared services, your profile information may be shared with other members to enable collaboration.

###  Pursuant To What Legal Bases Do We Process Your Information? 

We rely on a number of legal bases to use your information in the ways indicated above. These legal bases include where:

  * necessary to perform the contractual obligations in our agreement with you or your employer and provide services to you;
  * you have consented to the processing, which you can revoke at any time;
  * necessary to comply with a legal obligation, a court order, or to exercise or defend legal claims;
  * necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests; and 
  * you have expressly made the information public.

Note that we principally rely on consent (i) to send marketing messages, and (ii) for sharing data of event attendees with sponsors post event.

Where we process your information on the basis of legitimate interests, we do so as it is necessary to pursue our legitimate interests of providing and improving Forrester services for our customers. Forrester has a legitimate interest in understanding how our services are being used. We also pursue our legitimate interests of improving our services, efficiency, and determining the level of interest in services for customers by obtaining insights into usage patterns of the services.

Forrester has a legitimate interest in customizing your on-site experience to help you discover relevant research and topics. Forrester also engages third-party companies and individuals (such as research companies, and analytics providers) to help us operate, provide, and market the services. These third parties have only limited access to your information, may use your information only to perform these tasks on our behalf, and are obligated not to disclose or use your information for other purposes. Forrester may also use your information to maintain a secure Site, including sharing of your information for such purposes, because it is necessary to pursue our legitimate interests in ensuring the security of our services, including enhancing protection of our Site, intellectual property infringement and security risks of all kind. Forrester has a legitimate interest in working with service providers to make our services better even if some service providers we use are not strictly necessary for us to provide the Services.

Forrester may also process and share your personal information with a third party in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet legitimate national security or law enforcement requirements; defend against legal claims, to comply with a subpoena, court order, legal process, or other legal requirement; or when we believe in good faith that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with the law.

###  Cookies 

  * What are cookies?   
A cookie is a small text file that a website saves on your computer or mobile device when you visit the site. It enables the website to remember your actions and preferences (such as login, language, font size and other display preferences) over a period of time, so you don’t have to keep re-entering them whenever you come back to the site or browse from one page to another. 
  * What types of cookies does Forrester use? 
    * Necessary: cookies required for access to the Site and core functionality.
    * Behavior and analytics: cookies used to gather behavioral information through the Site; provide customized content and recommendations; and analytics.
    * Marketing: cookies that are used to deliver relevant advertising.
  * Behavioral information collected by our web analytics vendor is used to analyze data pertaining to visitor trends, research consumption, and research grading in order to improve our research, plan Site enhancements, and measure overall Site effectiveness. We may also use cookies or web beacons to help us offer you products, programs, or services that may be of interest to you and to deliver relevant advertising. We may use third-party advertising companies to help tailor Site content to users or to serve ads on our behalf. These companies may also employ cookies and web beacons to measure advertising effectiveness.
  * Aggregated (non-personally identifiable) user behavior collected through cookies or web beacons may be shared with our other third-party service providers to either analyze or execute marketing programs.
  * Please note that Forrester or other Forrester vendors or third-party advertisers may also use cookies that are independent of those placed by our analytics contractor (for example, to remember your password or tailor Site content).
  * Cookies and web beacons do not contain personally identifiable information; however, if you are a registered user, we may store this information with your registration information to enable us to better serve you. Use of cookies may also allow Forrester to automate your access to password-protected portions of the Site making it unnecessary for you to have to re-enter your password each time you visit our Site.
  * What can you do about cookies?  
You may choose to control and/or delete all cookies from your hard drive. If you delete a cookie, however, please be advised that some features of our Site may not be accessible to you. Another option available to you is to change the preferences or settings in your web browser to control cookies. In some cases, you can choose to accept cookies from a primary Site, block them from third parties, or clear out all cookies. 

###  Transfer Of Data 

  * We operate globally and may transfer your personal information to our affiliate companies or third parties in locations around the world for the purposes described in this privacy policy. Wherever your personal information is transferred, stored, or processed by us, we will take reasonable steps to safeguard the privacy of your personal information. Additionally, when using or disclosing personal information transferred from the European Union, we use standard contract clauses approved by the European Commission, adopt other means under European Union law for ensuring adequate safeguards, or obtain your consent.

## What You Can Do And Your Rights

  * You can unsubscribe from promotional emails you receive at any time by clicking the link at the bottom of the email and may disable notifications on your mobile device. You may not be able to opt-out of important service announcements and administrative messages.
  * You can choose to control and/or delete cookies from your hard drive. See the Cookie section above for more details.
  * You can choose to not let anyone scan a bar code at a Forrester event unless you want that sponsor to have your contact information. 
  * When attending a sponsored session at an event you can inform a Forrester representative that you do not want your information shared with the event sponsor.
  * There may be public areas of the Site that allow you to post or upload information. Any information you choose to upload or post can be viewed by all users. We discourage you from uploading any personal information in these areas of the Site.
  * If you are using Tap and you do not want your name or user ID associated with Your Taps, you can choose not to link to your Facebook profile, however, this may diminish your user experience and lower the credibility of Your Taps. You may delete your account and the Tap application from your mobile device if you no longer wish to access Tap, but Your Taps will remain on Tap even after such deletions. 
  * You have the following rights. Please note Forrester may have lawful reasons to deny requests related to the rights below: 
    * The right to be informed: You have the right to be informed of Forrester’s purposes for processing your personal data, Forrester’s retention periods for that personal data, and who it will be shared with.
    * The right of access: You have the right to access your personal data and supplementary information to allow you to be aware of and verify the lawfulness of the processing.
    * The right to rectification: You have the right to have inaccurate personal data rectified or completed if it is incomplete.
    * The right to erasure: You have the right to have your personal data erased from our systems.
    * The right to restrict processing: You have the right to request the restriction or suppression of your personal data.
    * The right to data portability: You have the right to obtain and reuse your personal data for your own purposes across different services.
    * The right to object: You have the right to object to processing based on legitimate interests or the performance of a task in the public interest/exercise of official authority (including profiling); direct marketing (including profiling); and processing for purposes of scientific/historical research and statistics.
    * Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling: You have rights related to automated decision making any profiling. Please note that Forrester does not make any such automated decision making or profiling. 

  * If you want to exercise any of your rights or need to contact Forrester’s Data Protection Officer, please email [privacy@forrester.com](mailto:privacy@forrester.com). You can always contact Forrester at +1 617-613-5730 or +1 866-367-7378 (toll-free in the US and Canada) should you have any questions or concerns.
  * You can go to Forrester’s [subscription center](https://www.forrester.com/trust/preferences) and select or change your contact preferences at any time.

###  Additional Information That May Be Of Interest 

  * Forrester account managers, analysts, and other members of the research staff can place research documents into a client’s Research Bookmarks. To prevent duplicate placement of research, research and account management employees can review the contents in this area.
  * We have implemented technical, administrative, and physical security measures that are designed to protect your information from unauthorized access, disclosure, use, and modification. Please be aware though that, despite our best efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable.
  * Forrester does not knowingly collect any personal information from children and does not market or offer services to children. You must be at least 13 years of age to access the Site.

###  Changes 

Changes to this policy may be posted from time to time. All versions will reflect a posting date. We encourage you to visit this page periodically for changes.

**Last updated October 22, 2018**
